

hello@mattcook.dev mattcook.dev

github.com/sciencefidelity linkedin.com/in/sciencefidelity 07712 296 146

I'm a front-end engineer specialising in **React** and **TypeScript**. I'm passionate about structured content, designing unique user experiences, and learning new front-end frameworks and programming languages. I regularly build and contribute to open-source projects, create internet art, and contribute to online hackathons. I speak fluent Russian, and regularly practice and teach meditation.

Employment

Front-End Developer

National Arts & Education Network, Wales (Sept 2019 - present)

- Developed a website with **React**, **Remix** and **TypeScript** to advertise professional development events for teachers and artists in the Expressive Arts Curriculum.
- Designed and implemented digital marketing tools that have increased ticket sales and course attendance by 300%.
- Designed a structured content strategy implemented with Sanity.io to be used by non-technical content editors.
- Developed a course platform with **React** and **Sanity.io** to present a series of Expressive Arts learning resources for teachers, including full text search with **Algolia**.
- Recently won a funding proposal to create a digital map of arts and culture venues throughout Wales that will use **React**, **Prisma** and **PlanetScale**.

Front-End Developer

Mid Wales Arts (July 2020 - present)

- Developed a multilingual React website with Next.js to provide a beautiful and intuitive user experience on all devices.
- Designed a custom i18n implementation of **Next.js** and **Sanity.io** that enables all slugs and routes to be localised into English and Welsh to improve SEO.
- Designed a structured content strategy with Sanity.io to create a streamlined user experience highlighting the diverse activities of a vibrant arts centre.
- Implemented a custom CMS with Sanity.io for editing of all website content by non-technical content editors.
- ▶ Increased website traffic by 1000%, visit duration by 400%, and reduced bounce rate.
- Implemented an e-commerce integration with Shopify, Sanity.io and Next.js to sell original artworks.

Freelance Web Developer (May 2012 - present)

- Development of unique websites for arts, culture and not-for-profit clients with front-end frameworks including **React**, **Svelte** and **Vue**.
- Design of custom content strategies with Sanity.io and Strapi, with integrated custom CMS implementations for non-technical content creators.
- Built custom multilingual WordPress and Drupal themes with JavaScript and PHP, with custom content types, plugins and WooCommerce integrations.

Studio Director (Oct 2011 - present)

Founded and continue to manage a charity providing affordable studios for 20 artists.

Freelance Artist (May 2002 - present)

- Regular creation of unique multimedia art projects all over the world in galleries, theatres and the public realm using digital media, sound, video, and electronics.
- Regular teaching of arts workshops for children and teachers in animation, creative web development, video production and digital competency.

Awards & Volunteering

Open Source

- Developed two IDE extensions for Nova with over 1200 active installations, providing LSP integration, syntax highlighting and completions for Dart and Flutter, and Astro.js.
- Designed and built an SEO preview plugin with **React** and **TypeScript** for integration with **Sanity Studio**.
- Recent contributions to popular open-source projects include Astro.js, Definitely Typed, Prisma and Sanity.io.

Empower

- Co-founded a charity to provide and promote online meditation experiences for children and adults, for use by teachers and healthcare professionals.
- Currently developing an iOS and Android app with React Native and TypeScript aimed at teachers and healthcare professionals to provide structured meditation classes.
- Currently designing and developing a website with React, Astro.js and Svelte, which includes a structured content strategy with Sanity.io.

Creative Wales Award (2014 - 2015)

Grant award for artistic and professional development to create a new body of video art presented on Vimeo, an artist website and blog, and run a mentoring program.

Education

I Speak...

University of Wales Institute, Cardiff BA (Hons) Fine Art. Time Based Practice. First. **English -** Native. **Russian -** Advanced and improving.